Denis K. Kikanzira

Sr. Security Analyst (eGRC)

Summary

Solutions-oriented IT Security Professional with extensive senior-level experience in system / network security analysis, information assurance, IT security governance and security administration. Solid background in information CyberSecurity Administration, compliance auditing and vulnerability / intrusion analysis, industry security standards and guidelines, along with project management.

Intuitive and highly analytical with in-depth knowledge of networking security technologies, architectures and platforms with the ability to apply them to the strategic benefit of the organization. Excellent capacity to work with IT managers to prioritize activities and achieve defined objectives; ability to translate business requirements into security solutions.

Strong knowledge of eGRC, FedRAMP, FISMA, NIST 800 series, DOD guidelines, FISCAM, PCI-DSS and HIPAA.

Experience

Sr. Security Analyst (eGRC) at Constellation West

September 2014 - Present

Sr. Security Engineer at Securicon, LLC

September 2013 - August 2014 (1 year)

Sr. Security Analyst at Missing Link Security

March 2012 - August 2013 (1 year 6 months)

IT Systems Engineer at Intelsat

June 2010 - March 2012 (1 year 10 months)

Systems Administrator at Henry M Jackson Foundation

December 2007 - June 2010 (2 years 7 months)

ICT Administrator at Makerere University Walter Reed Project

March 2005 - October 2007 (2 years 8 months)

Web Developer at Uganda Home Pages Ltd

September 2001 - March 2005 (3 years 7 months)

Education

University of Maryland University College

MSc. IT, Information Assurance, 2009 - 2010

Activities and Societies: Upsilon Pi Epsilon

Makerere University

Bachelors of IT, Computer Science, 2004 - 2007

Honors and Awards

Certificate of Appreciation

Denis K. Kikanzira

Sr. Security Analyst (eGRC)



Contact Denis on LinkedIn